Now I'm going to emphasize why it is
现在 我想强调一下
important to not just compute a sequence of configurations,
虽然 计算出一系列配置很重要
but also to decide when we're going to be in each configuration.
但是 决定我们何时到达这些配置同样重要
So let's say I told you that some car recently
假设我告诉你一些车最近
drove along this road following this trajectory.
沿着这条路上的这条轨迹行驶
If I asked you to describe what the driver did,
那么 如果我请大家描述司机是如何操作的
you might be tempted to say that they passed the slow moving vehicle or maybe,
大家可能会说司机超过了一辆慢车
you think they swerved to avoid a pothole.
或者说司机避过了一个坑
Well, let me tell you what actually happened up here,
那么 让我告诉你在这里到底发生了什么
we had a broken down vehicle stopped on the road,
这里有一辆坏在路上的车
and down here we have
这里有一辆快速行驶的车
a quickly moving vehicle that will travel the trajectory we just saw.
行驶的车会沿着我们刚看到的轨迹行驶
Now, I'm going to track the location of this vehicle with little blue dots.
现在 我将使用一些小蓝点跟踪这辆车的位置
Add one here for T equals zero.
这里加一个点 表示 T=0 的位置
In the next time step,
在下一个时间步进中
the vehicle has moved forward quite a bit and again and again,
车辆已经向前移动了相当一段距离 并且继续前进
but this time not as much because it started to slow down and slowing down again.
但是这次时间持续很短 因为该车开始减速 再减速
At this point, this vehicle would
在这个点上 车辆将变道
like to change lane in order to pass the stopped vehicle.
目的是越过停着的车辆
However, at the same moment it senses a vehicle
然而 同时 它又感应到另一辆车
arriving behind it in the other lane at high speed.
在另一条车道上飞驰而来
Therefore, it has to wait until this new car has passed it in order to change
因此 这辆车不得不等待 直到新出现的车越过它 然后再执行变道
lane which only gives it the option to come to a full stop and wait.
这时候 它不得不完全停下来
T=7, T=8 and T=9 when the red vehicle has passed it.
在 T=7, T=8 and T=9 的时间段 红色车辆越过了它
The blue vehicle decide that it's safe to keep driving.
蓝车的决策是 继续行驶是安全的
It does this by turning left and accelerating.
然后它左转 加速
It continues with the lane change maneuver,
它继续原来的变道动作
until it gets into the left lane where it keeps
最后它进入了左边车道 并继续加速
accelerating and accelerating until it gets to highway speed.
直到它的速度满足高速路的要求
Once it has passed the stop vehicle,
一旦它越过停着的车辆
it gets back into the right lane and continues on its way.
它会回到右方车道继续行驶
I told you this story using discrete time increments,
我讲解时 时间的增加是不连续的
but the vehicle was following a continuous path that looked something like this.
但是事实上 该车会沿着一条连续路径行驶 看起来是这样的
If we remove the dots,
如果我们擦掉这些点
we're left with the same path I asked you about in the beginning.
我们会得到一个路径 这个路径和我开始时请大家思考的路径相同
The problem was not incorporating timing into our planning,
问题的关键并不是没有将时间过程纳入规划
is that you don't tell the full story.
而是大家的思考欠缺一些方面
You describe the motion of your vehicle in the next few seconds,
大家描述了车辆在接下来几秒内的运动
but you don't actually specify where
但是大家没有指定在这个时间段的给定时间点上
the vehicle should be at a given time within this time frame.
车辆应该处于什么位置
When we were solving static maze'ss's problems this was fine but highways aren't mazess's.
当我们解决静态的梅斯问题时 并没有问题 但是高速路和梅斯问题不同
There is traffic on highways which means that
高速上有车流
the traversal space is constantly changing over time.
意味着行驶空间随着时间在不断变化
To avoid collision in dynamic environment,
在动态环境中 为了避免碰撞
we need to think about time as well.
我们需要把时间纳入考量
And that means that driving in traffic is fundamentally a three dimensional problem.
那意味着 在车流中驾驶从根本上而言是个三维问题
It is important to note that you have
这里有个非常重要的提醒
the same situation if you were using Cartesian coordinates.
如果你使用笛卡尔坐标系 你会遇到同样的情况
For any coordinates help us simplify the problem,
因为 无论我们用什么坐标系来简化我们的问题
but do not change the nature of the problem,
都不会改变问题的本质
which is planning a trajectory in dynamic environment.
那就是 - 在动态变化的环境中规划一条轨迹出来